Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 8 Month(s)

Highest Degree: M.Tech [Software Engineering]

Notice Period: 1 Month

Thushara Joseph (1) Featured

Front End Engineer | React | Angular.

Looking for opportunities in Bangalore, Pune, Hyderabad, Mumbai



Current Designation: Front End Engineer -Software

Development

Current Company: Singtel (Datasparks)

Current Location: thushara joseph

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Mumbai, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Front End Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application

Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution

Architecture, Angular 2, HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap, Java Script AJAX, JSON, Bootstrap, Node. js, REST API, Git

Verified: Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Eextensive experience in development of web applications with Front - End technologies using both Angular and React Stack. Strong web development skills with HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, Less/Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript (ES5/ES6), React, Redux, React Hooks, React context, Angular and JSON.

Experience in responsive web pages design with Media Queries, CSS Grid Layout, Flexbox and Bootstrap.

Work Experience

Singtel (Datasparks) as Front End Engineer -Software Development

Dec 2019 to Till Date

Project1: Mobility Dashboard in React

Developed the Front-End and User Interface applications using Javascript, Typescript, React

Developed Single Page Applications (SPAs) using React-Router and to enable navigation from one view to the next as clients performs application tasks.

Involved writing modules using React as a view engine to build component-based application.

Created reusable React components and managed application state with React Hooks and Context

SSR, prefetching achieved using Next.js.

Worked in Agile Methodologies for incremental development to deliver better application.

Used Material Design to theme the app.

Used SWR to handle refreshing of data from API for GET calls.

Creating Custom Hooks to handle common logics like api handling, auto height and with calculations, array manipulations

Project2: Management Console application in Angular

Moved existing AngularJS controllers and services to Angular 8 components for more responsive and less dependency.

Refactored the client-side validation to decouple the UI and business logic, reduced dependency and event listeners.

Implemented HTTP requests using RxJS Observable library to handle multiple values over time.

Experience in working with the advanced JavaScript such as ECMAScript 6 (ES6).

Used NPM to manage application dependency

ES6 and follow JSHint standard for high code quality.

Applied Semantic UI to design user interface such as Accordion, Tab and Modal.

Dentsu Aegis Network as Front End Engineer

Jun 2018 to Dec 2019

Designed the digital prototype for the product during the product design phase.

Hands on Experience on Angular 8 technology for one complete project in rebasing the UI of the application using the techniques in Angular 8.

Worked Extensively with Angular CLI for creating components, Services, pipes, Directives.

Used various Angular 2 custom directives and developed reusable components and templates that can be re-used at various places in the application.

Implemented HTTP requests using RxJS Observable library to handle multiple values over time.

Used charts frameworks like D3.js and Highcharts.js for developing and customizing multiple chart types.

Implemented GTM and GA for the application.

Involved in agile software methodologies using TEST DRIVEN DEVELOPMENT(TDD).

Used JIRA for bug tracking. Git is used as a version control tool and Jenkins is used for continuous integration of builds.

Matrix ComSec as Software Design and Analysis Engineer

Jun 2015 to Nov 2016

Requirement elicitation from global clients and converting them into user stories and flow charts. product designing and prototyping for multiple projects.

Product owner for a scrum team.

Presented prototypes and concept designs using tools like Illustrator, Photoshop & Sketch

Developed website redesign and improved conversions by 300%, using Javascript and HTML5

Collaborated effectively with the marketing and dev teams to achieve quarterly KPIs

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Institute for Technology and Management (ITM) in 2015

PG: M.Tech (Software Engineering) from National University of Singapore (NUS), Singapore in 2018

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Angular2			
HTML, CSS			
BOOTSTRAP, JavaScript			
AJAX AND JSON			
Node.js and REST APIs			
D3.js, Highcharts.js, Mapbox.js			
Git, SVN			
Mysql, Mogo DB			
JIRA			
Eclipse IDE, IntelliJ			
Visual Studio, Sublime Text			
Axure, InVision, sketch			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

1/22/2021	nttps://treesearcn.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=9b21bbe727e1411tbt0169655809b57c5a0t0a5919165c190217435e58			
Hindi				
Malayalam				
Gujarati				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time